■
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Iz          奈奈良
校对：Iz          总监   Iz
时间轴：今        后期：吉吉
《开心汉堡店》
第三季第七集
我还是不敢相信
Wow, still can't believe this sale.
六万张的抽纸纸巾才58块钱
Six thousand low-fold dispenser napkins for $58?
卖家脑子进水了吗
What are they thinking?
我也不懂
I don't know.
是吧  还是双层的呢
Yeah, and they're two-ply.
今天真是个好日子
This is... this is a great day.
难得的好日子
A really great day.
你看停车场多空旷啊
Wow, look how big and empty the parking lot is, huh?
我把方向盘交给你如何
What do you say you get behind the wheel?
我要方向盘干嘛
What would I do behind the wheel?
开车啊
Drive.
合法吗
Is that legal?
是不合法啦  但我像你这么大的时候
Well, no, but my father let me drive
我老爸就让我开车来着
when I was about your age.
就算是你帮老爸跑腿的奖励吧
Call it a perk for running errands with your dad.
我要发动了哦
Let's make this kitty purr.
来吧  试一下转弯
Mm, go ahead. Try a turn.
蒂娜  你哼哼什么  你做得很好啊
Tina, why are you groaning? You're doing fine.
放轻  蒂娜  放轻松  放轻松
Rela... Tina, relax. Easy, easy.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
蒂娜  这停车场就那么一辆车
Tina, you're kind of headed toward
你还偏往那个方向开是什么意思
the only other car in the lot.
时间还很充裕  蒂娜  转弯就行了
You have plenty of time to turn, Tina, so just go ahead.
左转右转都行
Turn one way or the other...
别忽左忽右的
You're just swerving back and forth.
就往一边转  蒂娜
Turn one way and stick with it, Tina.
蒂娜  我求你了  要么停车要么转弯
Tina, for the love of God, turn away or stop!
踩刹车  蒂娜  左边那个
The brakes, Tina! On the left!
你要撞上那辆车了
You're about to hit that car!
刹车  踩刹车
The brakes! Hit the brakes!
我的天  这下糟了
Oh, my God, it's bad.
我把这车毁了
I ruined the car!
没错  你的确把它毁了
You did. You really did.
好吧  这个...
Okay, uh... Well, that's... Ugh.
至少别人的车
At least there doesn't seem to be
貌似没什么损伤
any damage to the other car.
不  我看见凹痕了  那儿有个凹痕
No, I see a dent! There's a dent!
只是个印记  类似刮痕那样的
That-that's a ding. Not even. It's like a little scratch.
不  是凹痕
N-no, it's a dent!
好吧  我留个条行了吧
All right, we'll leave a note.
不过我还是想说
You know, then again, for all we know,
搞不好它本来就有的呢  对吧
that probably was there, right?
我们得留字条  我们得留字条
We have to leave a note! We have to leave a note!
好  好  这娃太实在了
Okay, okay! You're- You're so honest.
谁教你的
Who raised you?
我不知道
I don't know.
什...  是我  我教的
Da... It was me. I did.
你们怎么坐出租回来的
What's with the cab?
是啊  你的车呢
Yeah, where's the car?
车送修车店了
Um, the car is in the shop.
我们发生了一点小事故
There was a little accident and...
什么
What?!
-等下  琳  琳  -什么
- Wait, Lin, Lin. - What?
发生什么事了
What happened?
冷静  我们撞上了一辆停着的车
Calm down. We hit a parked car.
你们还好吧  到底怎么回事
Are you okay? What happened?
我的孩子  看着我
My baby, wa... Look at me.
快看着我  我的天哪
Look at me. Oh, God.
我们没事  蒂娜没事
We're fine. Tina is fine.
我的孩子  我的孩子
Oh, my baby. Oh, my baby.
等下  你们是怎么撞上停着的车的
Wait, how'd you manage to hit a parked car?
-你喝酒了吗  -不是
- Are you drunk? - No.
我闻到酒气了
You smell like wine.
我们从餐馆用品供应店出来
We-we were coming out of the restaurant supply store and...
等一下
Hold on.
开心汉堡店
Bob's Burgers.
你好  吉米
Oh, hi, Jimmy.
对  他就在我旁边
Yeah, he's right here.
吉米・派丝多打来的
It's Jimmy Pesto.
他想干嘛
Ugh, what does he want?
你好  吉米
Hello, Jimmy.
你好  鲍勃  想听敲门笑话吗
Hello, Bob, want to hear a knock-knock joke?
小孩常玩的一种文字游戏
-不想  -咚咚
- No. - Knock-knock.
我现在没那个心情
I'm really not in the mood.
-咚咚  -是谁
- Knock-knock! - Ugh, who's there?
你撞了我的车  你个二货
You hit my car, dumbass.
哈哈  敲门笑话中的经典
Eh, classic knock-knock.
开什么玩笑  那是你的车吗
You've got to be kidding me. That was your car?
你没听到我的敲门笑话吗
Did you or did you not hear my knock-knock joke?
好吧  听我说  事情是这样的
O-Okay, look, what happened was...
跟保险公司说去吧
Tell it to your insurance company.
拜托吉米  那样的话我的保险费率
Oh, come on, Jimmy. I don't want my rates to go up.
又该涨了  我会赔偿你的
I'll just pay whatever the damage is and...
门都没有  就凭你那点收入
No way. Not on your salary.
我可没时间等你制定一个
I don't have time for you to work out
每月还八分的赔款计划
an eight-cents-a-month payment plan.
穷鬼一个
Ha. He's poor.
好吧
Fine.
我去跟保险公司谈  再见
We'll go through my insurance. Good-bye!
-你那开车技术就顶个屁  -屁
- You drive like a fart! - Fart.
怎么回事
So what happened?
然后呢  我开着车
So anyway, I was driving, and I ran into what turned out
撞上了停车场上的吉米・派丝多的车
to be Jimmy Pesto's car in the parking lot.
-可老爸  是我开  -好了  蒂娜
- But, Dad, I was... - Come on, Tina.
帮我把纸巾搬到地下室去吧
Help me carry the napkins down to the basement.
-好吧  -搬个纸巾还要帮忙
- Okay. - Help you carry napkins?
老爸  别忘了抬腿
Yeah, Dad, be sure to lift with your legs.
用手推车好了
Use the hand truck.
一大把年纪了  不该让你搬东西的
You shouldn't be carrying anything at your age.
没错  你有孕在身  坐着吧  老爸
Yeah, you're pregnant. You sit down, Dad.
在你们的车修好之前
Hey, while your car is in the shop,
我可以用我的车载你们
I can drive you guys around.
谢谢你  莫特
Oh, thank you, Mort,
但我们现在不出门
but we don't need to go anywhere.
你是说我们可以坐灵车吗
We'd get to ride in the hearse?
要去的地方可多着呢
There's lots of places we need to go.
啥  要去哪儿
What? Where?
夜总会  日总会  烟雾缭绕的咖啡馆
Nightclubs, day clubs, smoky cafes...
-中国城  泰国城  -图书馆
- Chinatown, Thai Town... - Library.
太好了  那我们现在就走吧
Great, I'm heading out now if you want to come with.
散弹枪是我的
I call shotgun.
棺材是我的
I call coffin.
不公平  我要棺材
No fair, I want coffin!
很好  正中下怀
Good, it was a trick!
我好怕棺材的
I'm too scared to ride coffin.
我们就说开车的是我  明白吗
So we just have to say I was driving, okay?
那是说谎  是不对的
That's lying. That's not right.
你说得对  蒂娜
That's true, Tina.
说谎是不对的  你不应该说谎
Lying is wrong, and you should never do it.
例外是当一个叫吉米・派丝多的白痴
Unless an idiot named Jimmy Pesto
把你丢给保险公司的时候  也就是现在
makes you go through insurance, which he is.
所以这次我们不得不撒谎
So we have to lie this one time.
接下来呢  作伪证  贩卖人口吗
What's next? Perjury? Human trafficking?
我们以后得多交点保险费  这没关系
Look, our insurance will go up a little, but we'll be fine.
但千万不能告诉别人真相
We just can't tell anyone about it.
-妈妈也不行吗  -特别是你妈
- Even Mom? - Ugh, especially Mom.
她不会撒谎
She can't lie.
我也不会啊
But I can't lie, either.
听着  这其实都不算撒谎
You know what, it's not even really a lie.
这是个秘密
It's a secret.
是我俩的秘密
It's our shared secret.
如果有背景也许会容易点
Huh, maybe if I had a backstory?
背景
A backstory?
这剧本里我有没有男友呢
Do I have a boyfriend in this scenario?
我看还是关注主要剧情就好
Uh, we should probably just stick to the necessary facts.
好吧
Oh, okay.
好吧  这样
Fine, all right,
剧本里你有一个秘密男友
you have a secret boyfriend in this scenario.
一个你永远不能提起的男友
One that you can't ever talk about.
他叫什么
What's his name?
塞巴斯蒂安
Um, Sebastian.
他会打长曲棍球  还很爱我
He plays lacrosse, and he loves me.
但他爱曲棍球胜过爱我
Mm-hmm. But he loves lacrosse more.
-好吧  -他头发多长
- Uh, yeah. - How long is his hair?
我不知道  很油腻
I-I-I don't know, but it's greasy.
太好了
Yes.
莫特  你车的独特之处在哪儿呢
So Mort, what special features does this baby have?
独特之处  比如说什么
Special features? Like what?
比如浮油  要是有死者家属跟着你
You know, like an oil slick
就可以派上用场
in case you're being followed by mourners?
不  不  没那种东西
Oh, no, no, nothing like that.
你有锤子吗  要是死者复活
Is there a hammer in case
就可以派上用场
one of them comes back to life?
没  没有锤子
No, no hammers.
那你就是赤手空拳上阵了
I guess you have to use your bare hands then.
-你真可爱  -那是
- You're cute. - Yeah.
你怎么忽悠他们来的
Whoa, how'd you swing that?
护航的警察吗
Oh, the police escort?
送你们之外
In addition to giving you kids a lift,
我还要送尸体去葬礼
I'm also on my way to a funeral.
所谓一石二鸟嘛
Killing two birds with one stone.
这么说后面真的有尸体咯
So there's a dead body back there?
还有"两只鸟"
And two birds.
还有两片屁屁
And two buns!
冲冲冲冲
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
接招吧  条子
Take that, po-po!
拜托  孩子们  这不是
Come on, kids, please. This is not...
抱歉
Sorry!
快放浮油  冲啊
Oil slick, go.
你戴个头罩干嘛
Why are you wearing a hair net?
因为压力太大  我都脱发了
Because stress is making my hair fall out.
看看我
Look at me.
蒂娜  全家就你头发最多
Tina, you have the fullest head of hair in the family.
我要能有那发际线  叫我杀人都行
I would kill for that hairline.
我就知道你会杀人
I believe you would.
放轻松  放轻松
Take it easy. Take it easy.
这样是不对的  我会进监狱的
This is all wrong. I'm going to jail.
或下地狱的
Or hell.
或者地狱般的监狱
Or hell jail.
今天的午饭吃什么
What's for lunch today?
你的谎言
Your lies!
不要
No!
昨天就吃的这个
That's what we had yesterday.
我知道这事不容易
Look, I know it's hard,
可我保证会好起来的
but I swear it will get easier.
再坚持一下  我们可以的
Just hang in there; we'll get through this.
你好  请问需要点什么
Hey, there. What can I get for you?
我什么都不需要
Oh, I'm not having anything,
不过倒是有些问题要你来回答
but I do have a few questions.
我是蔡斯・卡明斯基  你的保险理算员
I'm Chase Kaminsky, your insurance adjuster.
那是什么声音
What's that sound?
有声音吗
Uh, uh, what sound?
我没听到啊
I don't hear anything.
那  那个啊  这下听到了
Oh that, that, yes, I hear that.
可能是我女儿
That's probably my daughter.
她没事吧
Is she all right?
我想她可能在唱歌
I-I-I think it's a song.
她总唱个不停  所以可能是首歌
She's always singing, so... it's probably a song.
你也知道  小孩子的音乐嘛
You know, kids and their music.
她晕倒了
She passed out.
我去看看她
Better go check on her.
一切顺利  蒂娜
Everything's fine, Tina.
你跟我出去
We're going to go out there
正常点  别想着犯了什么错
and act like we didn't do anything wrong,
我们也没犯错  基本上
which we didn't, kind of.
可跟老妈撒谎是一回事
But lying to Mom was one thing;
跟保险理算员撒谎又是另一回事了啊
lying to the insurance guy is another.
够了够了  别发出那种声音
Okay, stop, stop making that sound.
-他听得见  -好吧
- He hears it. - Okay.
行了  你就去地下室
All right, let's-let's have you go
随便扫扫什么
down to the basement and, um, sweep something.
-扫灰尘吗  -对  扫扫灰尘
- Like dirt? - Yes, like dirt.
当时我停着呢  可我以为车还在开
So, I was in park, but I thought it was in drive,
于是我就想了啊  "为啥我不动了呢"
so I was thinking, "Uh, why am I not moving?"
我理解  是人都干过那样的事儿
Yeah, well, we've all done that.
我是没干过  不过有人一定干过
I mean, I haven't, but somebody must have.
像你  不就这么做了
We... you did.
是啊  我这么做了
Yeah, I did.
老天
Oh, God.
这是我女儿蒂娜
Uh, this is my daughter, Tina.
她笑的声音也是不太正常
Laughing is another one of her noises.
她是在笑吗
Oh, is that laughing?
当时我和我爸在车上
I was in the car with my dad.
她在副驾驶座上
Uh, in the passenger seat, she was.
对  就是副驾驶坐的地方
Yeah, where passengers sit.
对了  我开进停车位后
Right, so after I put it in park,
车还动着  我就想"车在空档上吗"
and I was moving, I thought, "Am I in neutral?"
于是我就挂了档  身子还往前一冲
So I shifted into gear and lurched forward.
然后一只蝴蝶从窗户飞进来
And then a butterfly flew in the window
老爸就开始拍它
and Dad started swatting at it.
蝴蝶
A butterfly?
什么蝴蝶  蝴什么蝶
What butterfly? Wha-What butterfly?
琳达  孩子们
Hey, Linda, kids.
这位是蔡斯  保险公司的人
Uh, this is Chase. He's from the insurance company.
我正跟他回想当时的事呢
I was just telling him what happened, uh...
没错  我...
Uh, yes, I was...
我正说到蝴蝶的部分
I was just getting to the butterfly part of the story.
开始我还以为是蜜蜂  把我吓坏了
I thought it was a bee, and I was startled.
然后我就使劲拍它
So I was, ah... swatting at it.
老爸竟然怕蝴蝶
Dad's scared of butterflies.
不是吧  老爸  快看  这有只瓢虫
Uh-oh, Dad, look out. There's a ladybug!
别闹  好了  所以
Stop it. All right, so, uh,
回到这个故事  蔡斯
anyway, back to the story, uh, Chase.
不对  不是故事  是事实
Uh, I mean, not a story; it's the truth.
然后我就打了方向盘
Um, so I swerved and...
接着一只鸬鹚飞进来了
A cormorant flew in the window.
鸬鹚是什么
What's a cormorant?
就是一种海鸟
It's a kind of seabird.
学校里教过的
We learned about them in school.
中国人用它来捕鱼
In China they use them to catch fish.
行了  蒂娜多谢
Yeah, thanks, Tina.
我差点忘记还有鸬鹚
Sorry I left out the cormorant.
鸬鹚  那可是个吉兆
A cormorant? What an auspicious sign.
总之  我就是这么撞的车
Anyway, that's how I hit the car.
先是蝴蝶  然后是鸬鹚
Butterfly, then cormorant.
-知道了  -真的吗
- Okay! - Really?
我们会马上处理你的索赔
We'll get your claim check cut right away.
感谢你的回顾  鲍勃
Thanks for your business, Bob.
谢谢你才是
Thank you.
很简单嘛  对吧
That was easy, right?
还有件事
One more thing. Aah! Aah!
我突然想问你
It just occurred to me to ask you...
果然逃不掉
Here it comes.
我这周日举办烧烤派对
I'm hosting a barbecue this Sunday.
承办人来不了了  还好遇到了你
My caterer fell through. Boom, I meet you.
你觉得呢
What do you say?
你以前干过这个吗
You ever take this show on the road?
承办派对吗
Oh, um, cater your party?
听起来不错  我们去
Sounds great. We'll do it.
可我们的助手只有这些孩子
Our only other employees are the kids.
那也  没问题吗
Is that... is that okay?
没问题
Great!
给你我电话
Here's my number. Huh.
周日见了
See you all on Sunday.
好的
Great.
这车的厕所在哪  这下面吗
Where's the bathroom in this thing? Under here?
不不  不在那儿
No. No, it's not there.
-好吧  我凑合用吧  -不不
- Yeah, it's fine. - Well no, just...
你就不能再憋会吗
Can you just hold it a little longer?
-这也难不倒我  -别别  求你了
- Well, it's not a problem. - No, no, please.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我十分钟后还要去见一个丧夫的寡妇
I'm meeting a grieving widow in ten minutes.
我也想小便了  看哪
Oh, I have to go, too. Hey, look!
"三室两卫"
"Three bedroom, two bath."
我们问题都能解决了
We can both go.
好吧
Ah, all right.
但得快点
But make it quick.
要出来了  要出来了
Got to go. Got to go. Got to go.
里面还好吧
Everything okay in there?
好得很
Everything's great.
我先撒了泡尿  然后顺理成章
I had to pee, but one thing led to another.
冲了个澡
Bam, I showered.
我们的祖父死了  就在外面
So our grandpa died. That's him out front.
躺在棺材里
He's in the to-go box.
他的遗愿就是要下葬在他被杀的屋子里
His last wish was to be buried at the house he was murdered in.
对  还要用谋害他的那把铲子陪葬
Yeah, with the shovel he was murdered with.
你能相信他是被铲子毒死的吗
Can you believe he was poisoned with a shovel?
房子我们要了
We'll take it!
-孩子们  -时机正好
- Kids. - Ah, perfect timing.
莫特司机  给这伙计开个合适的房价
Mortimer, give this fellow a fair price for the house,
我们在车里等你
and we'll meet you in the car.
谢谢你送他们  莫特
Hey, thanks for the lift, Mort.
我们应该不会太久
Uh, shouldn't be more than a couple hours, so, uh...
你看你是在这儿等还是先回去
are you gonna wait here or come back?
我回家也要一个小时
Well, it's an hour back to my place,
我就在车里等吧
so I guess I'll just sit in the hearse.
或许我可以在后座睡一觉
Maybe grab a nap in the back.
在灵车的后座睡觉
Uh-huh. A nap in the back of a hearse?
是谁说殡葬业者古怪的
Who says morticians are creepy?
现如今油价越来越贵了
Ha-ha. Well, all this gas is getting pretty expensive.
虽说灵车不耗油
A hearse doesn't exactly sip gas.
但这还是辆挺大的车
It's a big vehicle, you know? Uh-huh.
所以  如果你愿意分担点费用
But you know, if you would like to chip in
-那就太好了  -一会儿见
- that would be so great because... - Great, we'll see you in a few.
好的  好吧
Okay. All right.
一会儿见  没关系
See you soon. That's fine.
我们到这儿来干嘛
Why are we even here?
你不是说撒了那个谎就结束了吗
You said it would all be over after the one lie.
我们也不能拒绝蔡斯啊  蒂娜
Well, we couldn't exactly say no to Chase, Tina.
那会让事情更糟
That would make it worse.
我保证  烧烤派对之后
After the barbecue, I promise,
一切都会恢复正常
everything will go back to normal.
会吗
Will it?
还是那只不过是另一个谎言
Or is that another lie?
别这样  你冷静点
Whoa, easy. You've gotta calm down.
让我看看你"一切都很好"的脸
Let's, let's, let's see your "Everything is okay" Face.
不不不
Um, no, no, no,
那  那不是  那...
that's, that's not, that's...
-不  不行  不是这种  -这样吗
- No, that's bad. No, don't do that face. Like, like this?
不是  别再做那种脸了
No. Just stop doing the face.
这样呢
How about this?
你就跟我待在烤架这边好了
And stay with me here by the grill.
这样你流汗才不会让人起疑
That way your sweat will look more natural.
然后一只蝴蝶飞了进来
So then a butterfly spooks him,
接着他就把我们的车给撞了个稀巴烂
and he crashes our freaking car!
你太太在那边聊你那起车祸
Hey, your wife has 'em roaring over there,
可是引起了不小的轰动呢
talking about your little fender-bender.
蒂娜  我马上回来
Uh. Uh, Tina, I'll be right back.
别让肉掉地上地上就行
Just try and keep the meat off the ground. Okay...
你听过蝴蝶效应吗
You heard of the butterfly effect?
蝴蝶一扇翅膀
If a butterfly flaps its wings,
鲍勃就撞车
Bob crashes his car!
好了  琳达
Okay, Linda.
我们  过来坐会儿吧
Let's, uh, settle down.
怎么了  我在聊天呢
Oh, what? I'm making conversation.
他还敢说我开车技术烂
And he says I'm a bad driver!
蒂娜
Tina!
快给消防部门打电话
Oh, call the fire department!
我的脸
Ooh, my face!
蒂娜  没人要责怪你
Tina, no one's blaming you for this,
可你到底做了什么
but what wrong thing did you do?!
我不知道  我就只是像往常一样烤肉啊
I don't know. I was cooking like normal.
或许我火加得太旺了
Maybe I had the flame too high?
你为什么要让我接近火
Why would you let me around fire?
好吧  蒂娜  冷静
All right, Tina, calm down.
这  这很糟糕
This is, this is bad,
但这也是意外
but it was an accident.
我们  我们去跟蔡斯道歉
We'll, we'll tell Chase we're sorry.
告诉他我们在车祸的事上撒了谎
And that we lied about the car accident.
啥  不  不不不不
What?! No. No-no-no-no-no-no.
我们已经走得太远了
We're, we're in too deep now.
我们得按原计划进行
We have to stick to our story.
太可怕了  太可怕了
Oh, this is horrible. It's horrible!
我们把那倒霉鬼的房子给烤了
We barbecued that poor man's house.
等下  "我们"是谁
Wait, who's this "We"?
蒂娜玩火的时候
I was locking Gene in the garden shed
我可是忙着把吉恩锁花棚里呢
when Tina was playing Firestarter.
我忙着像小鼹鼠一样挖洞呢
I burrowed out like a little mole!
露易丝说得对
Louise is right.
-我是罪魁祸首  是扫把星  -你是
- I'm a firestarter and a jinx. - Yep.
我会害了我们全家
And I'm going to destroy this family.
你就是我变胖的罪魁祸首
You're the reason I'm fat!
-我知道  -我的天哪  蔡斯
- I know. - Oh, my God, Chase.
我  我不知道该说什么好了
I, I don't know what to say.
我们  我们非常抱歉
We're, we're so sorry.
鲍勃  没关系
Bob, it's okay.
这次的烧烤派对还是在以往的水平之上的
This was still a better-than-average party for me.
真的吗  可  可你的房子
Really? But your, but your house.
你一级棒的房子给烧没了
Your-Your really nice house is gone!
你可能没想到  我买保险了
Well, this might surprise you. I have insurance!
是没错  我一生的回忆
Yeah, I lost a lifetime of memories
和我的猫小雪都离我而去了
and my cat Spritzal.
我杀了你的猫
I killed your cat?!
没有  小雪上周就死了  自然死亡
Well, no, Spritzal died last week. Natural causes.
她这会儿应该正往上帝的鞋里撒尿呢
She's, uh, she's peeing in God's shoes now.
没那么快啦
Too soon!
但她的骨灰在房子里
But her ashes were in there.
技术上来说  它们还在  对吧老兄
Well, technically, they still are, aren't they, buddy?
好了  你们都回家吧
Look, you all go home
别把这件事放在心上  知道吗
and just forget about this, okay?
看到没人受伤我就谢天谢地了
I'm just so grateful that no one got hurt.
看路
Ow. Coming through!
我是罪魁祸首  是扫把星
I'm a firestarter and a jinx.
我会害了我们全家
And I'm going to destroy this family.
我们已经走得太远了  得按原计划进行
We're in too deep now! We have to stick to our story!
怎么
Huh?! Wha...?!
-怎么  怎么了  -吉恩
- Wha...? Wha...? - Gene!
发生什么事了
What the heck is going on?
我胃绞痛
My stomach is in knots.
你又把绳子吃下去了吗
Did you eat rope again?
蒂娜宝贝  你是在想火灾的事吗
Tina, sweetie, is this about the fire?
房子烧了还可以重修啊
Because houses can be rebuilt.
没人受伤就好了  亲爱的
No one was in it, honey.
可我的良心还被火烤着呢
But my conscience is still on fire.
我受够了  我不能看蒂娜再这样下去
Okay, enough. I, I can't stand to see Tina like this.
听着  关于那天是谁开车的事
Listen, I lied about who was driving our car
我撒谎了
during the accident. Huh?!
我让蒂娜在停车场开了一小下
I let Tina drive a little in the parking lot.
不公平  莫特都没让我们开
No fair! Mort doesn't let us drive!
因为我撒的谎  之后事情变得越来越糟
And then I made everything worse by lying about it.
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
因为你是个藏不住秘密的人
Because you're terrible at keeping secrets.
什么都能给你说漏了
You just blurt everything out.
抱歉我们迟到了  鲍勃拉肚子了
Sorry we're late! Bob had diarrhea!
面包黄油一块块
Running down the gutter
通通拉进马桶盖
with the piece of bread and butter, diarrhea.
琳
Lin!
我爱你  老妈
I love you, Mom.
总之  我不该瞒着你们的
Anyway, I shouldn't have kept this from you.
我做错了
I was wrong.
别闹
Stop it.
我明天一早
I'm going down to Chase's office
就去蔡斯的办公室跟他坦白
first thing in the morning to come clean.
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
很好  这下你可你尽管讲真话了
Yes! Good. We'll tell some truth!
"你们的车修好之前
"Hey, while your car's in the shop,
我可以载你们"
I can drive you guys around."
我讲那个干嘛  我脑子进水了吗
Why did I say that? What's wrong with me?
你们好呀
Oh, hey, guys!
有什么需要我帮忙吗
What can I do for you?
你好  蔡斯
Hi, Chase.
我有事要告诉你
Uh, I have something I need to tell you.
是来告诉我的鱼死了吗  我已经知道了
Is it about my dead fish? 'Cause I already know.
当时开车的不是我  是蒂娜
I wasn't driving when I had the car accident. Tina was.
真的  是我开的
It's true. I was.
我知道啊
I knew that.
-你知道  -你知道
- You knew? - You knew?
你难道以为
What, you thought you were
编个蝴蝶和鸟的烂故事
fooling me with that cockamamie story
就能骗到我吗
about a butterfly and a bird?
蝴蝶和鸬鹚
A cormorant.
随便吧  我当然知道
Whatever. Of course I knew!
我想说与人方便自己方便嘛
I figured if I scratched your back, you'd scratch mine.
等等  我给你什么方便了
Wait. I-I don't want to scratch your back.
你给了啊
You already did.
蒂娜"意外造成的火灾"  才不是意外
Tina's "Accidental" Fire? No accident.
是意外  我发誓
It was an accident, I swear!
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
我们都是一条船上的  朋友
We're all in on this, compadres!
我对那起车祸睁一只眼闭一只眼
I looked the other way on your fender-bender.
你就帮我烧房子
You gave me a convenient cover to burn down my house.
你为什么要烧自己的房子
Why would you burn down your own house?
因为我可以拿到两倍的赔偿金
'Cause I'm covered for twice what it's worth.
如果蒂娜是放火的那个人
And no one is gonna question my claim
就没人会对我的索赔提出质疑了
when little Tina was left in charge of the grill.
你怎么知道我会烧了房子呢
How did you know I was going to start a fire?
不是你
Well, you didn't.
烧房子的是我的好帮手  无味汽油
My good buddy odorless kerosene did. Ugh!
这么说我不是扫把星
So I'm not a jinx.
我真不敢相信你在说什么
I, I can't believe what you're saying.
这个你总信吧  这是你的那份
Well, believe this. It's your cut!
我的
My cut?
我才不要你的钱
I'm... I'm not taking your money.
好好想想吧  你们俩
Oh, think about it, you two.
我们可以组成保险界的"神勇三蛟龙"
We'll be the three amigos of insurance fraud.
《神勇三蛟龙》是一部美国喜剧电影
讲述三个银幕英雄被村民邀请前去对抗不法之徒
餐厅可向来是灾难不断的地方
Restaurants are disaster magnets!
烟囱堵塞  失足滑倒  还有她
Broken pipes, slip-and-falls, her.
我会保证你们拿到最高的赔偿
I make sure you get the maximum payout,
当然  要扣去我的佣金
minus a small percent, of course.
我们才不会骗保
Hey, we're not gonna commit insurance fraud.
也是  那不太像你会做的事
Yeah, that doesn't sound like something you'd do.
不对  你已经做了嘛
Oh, wait, you already did!
你老爸可能会坐牢
Your daddy could go to jail!
蔡斯  你别开玩笑了
Chase, you can't be serious...
我可是比法官还严肃
Huh! Huh! Serious as a judge.
对了  法官非常重视保险理算员的证词
Judges, by the way, are most interested in the testimony
而我会说出对你不利的证词
of the insurance adjuster. And I will testify against you.
有了  你们可以把地下室淹了
Oh, I got it! You'll flood your basement!
你为什么要这样对我们
Why are you doing this to us?
因为你们是我的摇钱树啊
Because you're my golden goose.
我可不愿错失这个机会
And I'm not letting you get away.
你真是我见过最烂的保险理赔员
You are the worst insurance adjuster.
但却是世界上最好的叔叔
But the world's greatest uncle.
也就是说  蔡斯威胁我们
So, Chase is blackmailing us.
如果我们不按照他的计划
And if we don't go along with his scam
淹了我们的地下室的话  他就会去告我
and flood the basement, he's gonna turn me in.
淹地下室
Flood the basement?
可我做拼贴画的材料都放在那儿呢
But my collage supplies!
不就是旧杂志嘛  老妈
They're just magazines, Mom.
那些可都是九十年代的《大都会》杂志
They are '90s Cosmopolitans from the '90s.
琳  回到我们被威胁的事上来
Lin, let's focus on the blackmailing.
搞死那个狗娘养的
We gotta take that son of a bitch down!
注意语言
Language.
-抱歉  老妈  -蒂娜说得没错
- Sorry. Mom. - Tina's right.
我们得想个法子
We need to come up with an idea
来摆脱当前这个困境
to get us out of this.
够了  蒂娜  让人慎得慌
Tina, stop doing that. It's disturbing and scary.
等等  有了
Wait. That's it!
什么
What is?
我们吓吓蔡斯
What if we scare Chase so bad
让他再也不愿见我们怎么样
he'll never want to see us again?
也许能行
Hmm. That could work.
吓他  怎么吓
Scare him? How?
早上好  鲍勃
Good morning, Bob!
还是我该叫你罗勃
Or should I call you "Rob"
Rob可作为姓氏  也有抢劫的意思
因为我们要一起骗钱嘛
since we're gonna be stealing money together?
抱歉  这个段子太妙了  我没忍住
I'm sorry. It was too good to resist.
呵呵  好好笑
Yeah, that was hilarious.
我要告诉你的是  我的地下室被淹了
Uh, so anyway, my basement flooded.
别担心  我们有保险呢
Luckily, we're covered.
鲍勃  你能叫孩子们上来一下吗
Uh, Bob, will you send the kids up?
-早饭快凉了  -他们没在这下面
- Their breakfast is getting cold. - They aren't down here.
你在说什么  他们在下面啊
What are you talking about? Of course they are.
他们在地下室玩呢
They were playing down in the basement.
地下室
The basement?!
鲍鲍  怎么了
Bobby, what's the matter?
我的孩子
My babies!
不
No...!
我的天哪  不
Oh, my God, no...!
我做得太过了  看看我都干了什么
I went too far! What have I done?!
我的孩子  我的孩子死了
My kids...! My children are dead!
鲍鲍  为什么会这样
Bobby, why?!
鲍勃  我不行了  我从没遇过...
Bob, I can't handle this! I never saw this...
我先走了  抱歉
Okay, I'm leaving! I'm sorry!
你再也不会见到我了
You'll never hear from me again!
表演结束
And... scene. Eh?
我们三个都演得不错  对吧
Great performances by all three of us, huh?
你猜到了
Oh. You figured it out.
拜托  你该不是以为
Come on. You didn't really expect me
我真的会信吧  鲍勃
to buy that, did you, Bob?
算是吧  是的
Uh, sorta. Yes.
你演技太烂了  你直接把门关了
Your acting is terrible. You closed the door.
都没想到要去救你的孩子
You didn't even try to resuscitate your kids!
是  因为他们憋气只能憋那么久
Yeah, It turns out the kids can't hold their breath that long.
本来想给他们弄个通气管的  但
And we were gonna give 'em snorkels, but, uh...
通气管
Snorkels.
算了  不重要了
Yeah, uh, you know what? Never mind.
通气管
Snorkel.
孩子们  上楼来吧
Kids, come upstairs.
我们现在来搞定这份表格吧
Now let's get this paperwork started!
让索赔进行起来
Get this claim processed!
别忘了  这件事你知我知
And remember, this stays just between us.
千万别告诉别人
No one can ever know.
鲍勃  琳  很好  你们都在
Bob, Lin, oh, good. You're, you're both here.
是这样  我有些话想跟你们说
Listen, I, I got something stuck in my craw.
现在不是时候  莫特
Not a good time, Mort.
这种事什么时候说都不是时候
Uh, you know, it's never a good time for these things.
你们是我的邻居  我喜欢你们
You're my neighbors and I love you,
我也喜欢你的孩子
and I, I love your kids.
至少某种程度上是  可我不是开出租的
I mean, up to a point. But I'm not a taxi, okay?!
好吧  抱歉
All right. Sorry.
我没控制好  有点太夸张了
That came out wrong. A little over the top.
让我  让我重新来过
Let me, let me start over.
我们明天就能拿回车了
Look, we're getting our car back tomorrow.
所以就不需要你载我们了  莫特
So we don't need any more rides, Mort.
没错  我们在你门前
Yeah, we left you a note
留了一张纸条和一包礼物以表感谢
and a thank-you package on your doorstep.
是这样啊  好吧
Oh, so you did. Okay.
你们太客气啦
Well, I mean, that wasn't necessary.
真是个愉快的惊喜  好吧  那我走了
What a lovely surprise. All right, I'm gonna go now.
好了  蔡斯  我们的计谋被你发现了
Okay, Chase. You, you caught us.
但你这样是在玩火  火
But you're playing with fire... Fire.
也是在浪费水
...and water, literally.
最终总会有人受伤的
And eventually, somebody is going to get hurt.
吉恩  够了
Gene, stop it!
你这样是在侮辱我  鲍勃
Don't insult me, Bob.
你还是个新手  我可是专业级的了
You're new to this. I'm the pro.
我过去已经策划过上百个阴谋
I've pulled hundreds of scams,
未来还会继续
and I'm gonna pull hundreds more.
我在想  下一次我们可以搞搞供电系统
Now for our next fraud, I'm thinking lightning.
来个电路短路就可以大搞破坏
A big surge could mess up
这么多昂贵的家用电器  是不是很疯狂
all these incredibly expensive appliances. Am I nuts?
-是  -好了  我先去处理这个案子
- Yes. - Well, off to process this flood claim.
再聊  搭档
Talk soon, partner!
我的上帝  我们永远摆脱不了这个人了
Oh, my God. We're stuck with this guy forever.
就好像我牙上的这片燕麦一样
Like me and this piece of corn in my teeth.
-对吧  燕麦兄  -是吗
- Right, corn? - Are we?
我过去已经策划过上百个阴谋
I've pulled hundreds of scams,
未来还会继续
and I'm gonna pull hundreds more.
蒂娜  太棒了
Ha! Tina, that's brilliant!
是吗  她做的时候就棒了
Oh, sure, when she does it, it's brilliant.
让那个骗子等着吃牢饭吧
That scammer is going to the slammer!
再见了  宝贝儿
Buh-bye, baby!
蒂娜  你知道这意味着什么吗
Tina, do you realize what this means?
你拯救了我们全家
You saved the family.
我想这大概就是学开车的意义吧
I guess it's all part of learning to drive.
摁这个
Uh, the, this one.
我在想  下次我们可以搞搞供电系统
For our next fraud, I'm thinking lightning!
鲍勃  你看
Hey! Hey, Bob! Bob, look!
那就是你
That's you.
这周终于过去了
Well, I'm glad this week is behind us.
这是我人生中最糟糕的一周了
This was the worst week of my life.
但我个人表现得还不错
But I'm better for it.
你说这是你最糟的一周  蒂娜
This was the worst week of your life, Tina?
你又撞了车  又烧了房子
You got to crash a car and burn down a house!
而我什么也没做
I got to do nothing!
行了  露易丝  给  这个给你摔
Fine. Here, Louise, you can break this plate.
不公平  我也要
No fair! I want one!
感觉不错  我要再摔一个
That felt good. I want another one!
不行  到此为止
No, that's it.
-给我一个  -住手
- Here, give me one! - Stop!
琳  你在干嘛
Lin, what are you doing?
怎么了嘛  我  我讨厌这些盘子
What? They're... I hate these plates.
别摔盘子了  琳
Stop breaking plates! Lin!
-好好玩  -摔呀
- it's fun. - Smash!
-看我来个一石二鸟  -不
- Watch me break this plate and the window! - No!